<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An account of the sessions of Parliament in Ireland, 1692</title>
            <author>Ireland. Parliament.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1693</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 36 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 16 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A45963</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing I297</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R16095</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">11849811</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 11849811</idno>
            <idno type="VID">49925</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A45963)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 49925)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 498:33)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An account of the sessions of Parliament in Ireland, 1692</title>
                  <author>Ireland. Parliament.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 28 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for J.T.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1693.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Bristol Public Library, Bristol, England.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Ireland --  Politics and government --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:49925:1"/>
            <p>AN ACCOUNT OF THE SESSIONS OF Parliament IN Ireland, 1692.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>J. T.</hi> MDCXCIII.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:49925:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:49925:2"/>
            <head>AN ACCOUNT Of the SESSIONS OF Parliament IN Ireland, 1692.</head>
            <p>THIS Kingdom having been ever ſince the Years 1665 without a Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament, to the great diſcouragement and Prejudice of the Proteſtant and <hi>Engliſh</hi> In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tereſt here: It is not to be wondred, if the firſt Report of a Parliament, graciouſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly deſigned by their preſent Majeſty's to
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:49925:3"/>be held the latter end of this Year, em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployed the Thoughts and Diſcourſes of all Proteſtants, and filled them with deſires to ſee ſo good a Deſign put in Execution, which was expected at the Lord Lieute<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant's Arrival; his Excellency Landed on the twenty fifth day of <hi>Auguſt,</hi> and Writs were immediately iſſued for a Parliament to meet on the fifth of <hi>October</hi> following.</p>
            <p>Every body began then more cloſely to conſider and Enquire, as well what could be, as what was likely to be done in this Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament.</p>
            <p>It was not doubted, but their Majeſties Occaſions in this Kingdom, wanted Supp<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ies of Money, which People were generally and chearfully diſpoſed to comply with, but the Anſwer of one of his Excellencies Secreta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries to a Member of the Houſe of Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons a few days before the Parliament ſat, was a little unaccountable; that there were no other Bills deſigned to be tendered to the Houſe this Seſſion, but only three, <hi>viz.</hi> An Act of Recognition, an Act for Confirm<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Acts of Settlement and Explanation;
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:49925:3"/>and an Act declaring all Attainders, and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Acts of the late Pretended Parliament, void, tho' at the ſame time another Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man belonging to the Council, declared that other Bills would be then alſo tender'd, name<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, An Act for Confirming the Articles of <hi>Limrick</hi> (the firſt Article of which, if con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firmed, would make Popery an Eſtabliſhed Religion; and the ſixth would deprive all Proteſtants of their Actions againſt the Papiſts, by whom they were Plundered, even while they lived in Peace with them) and alſo Money-Bills, a Member of the Houſe of Commons (then preſent when this was o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>penly ſpoken) anſwered, that the Houſe would conſider well of thoſe Acts before they paſſed them, but the ſame Perſon re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plyed, that it would be in vain to trouble themſelves about it, aſſuring them they were as well Debated already as was need<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful; and they had nothing elſe to do, but to paſs them; and added, that If any Scruple was made about them, there would never again be a Parliament in <hi>Ireland.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Theſe and ſuch like Diſcourſes common in Town, took off the pleaſure and ſatisfac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:49925:4"/>People had in the hopes of an happy Iſſue of this Parliament.</p>
            <p>On <hi>Wedneſday</hi> the <hi>5th. October</hi> the Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament being met, and the Commons ſent for up to the Lords houſe, his Excellency was pleaſed to declare in his Speech; <hi>Their Majeſties Command to him of calling this Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament immediately after his Arrival, and their goodneſs in reſtoring to this Kingdom a bleſſing of which it had for ſo many years been deprived, a Legally Conſtituted and Aſſembled Parliament, by the long Intermiſſion of which, the Engliſh in this Kingdom had been in great danger of loſing both their Religion and Liberty, and in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vited them with many grateful arguments to paſs ſuch Laws as might ſettle and ſecure them both for the future; concluding with a demand of a ſupply, and promiſe</hi> of repreſenting their ſervices well to their Majeſties.</p>
            <p>The Commons being returned to their Houſe, proceeded to chooſe their ſpeaker, and ſeveral of the Members having been in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formed that his Excellency wou'd be well pleaſed with their Choice of Sr. <hi>Richard Le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vinge</hi> their Majeſties Solicitor General, the Houſe ſoon came to a Reſolution in it, thoſe that were propoſed for it having before (at
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:49925:4"/>his Excellencies deſire) waved their own pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tenſions thereto; and both they and others who have ſince lain under the diſpleaſure of the Government uſed their utmoſt endeavors in the Houſe for effecting it; ſo that Sr. <hi>Rich<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ard</hi> was choſen Speaker, without thoſe heats that had been ſo frequent and violent in former Parliaments in <hi>Ireland.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Speaker being choſen the Members took the Oaths &amp; ſubſcribed the Declaration appointed by the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Act, &amp; then adjourn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed to <hi>Friday</hi> the ſeventh, on which day his Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cellency had directed them to preſent their Speaker, they then met, but were informed that his Excellency was indiſpoſed, and cou'd not come to the Houſe of Lords; an Addreſs therefore being made to him to know his further pleaſure therein, he was pleaſed to appoint <hi>Monday</hi> the tenth for that purpoſe.</p>
            <p>The Houſe having received this Anſwer, a motion was made that the Members who were returned for ſeveral places might have leave in the mean time to make their Electi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on for which place they wou'd ſerve, and that Warrants thereupon may Iſſue, and ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:49925:5"/>Preſidents in point were urged for it, but it was oppoſed, becauſe the Speaker thought not fit to act before his approbation; to the delay of publick buſineſs almoſt three days.</p>
            <p>On Monday the tenth, the Lord Lieute<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant came to the Houſe of Lords, and appro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved the Speaker.</p>
            <p>The Commons being returned to their Houſe, an Addreſs of thanks was Immedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ately voted to his Excellency for his Speech, and a Committee appointed to Meet the ſame afternoon to prepare it; and leſt the time ſpent in preparing it ſhou'd be inter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preted to proceed from want of Reſpect, it was voted that the Members of the Houſe that were of the Privy Council, ſhou'd attend his Excellency in the afternoon, and acquaint him with the ſaid Vote, and on <hi>Thurſday</hi> fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowing the Speaker attended by the whole Houſe, preſented the ſaid Addreſs.</p>
            <pb n="7" facs="tcp:49925:5"/>
            <p>The reſt of this day, and of <hi>Tueſday</hi> the <hi>11th.</hi> was ſpent in determining the Choice of Members doubly Elected, in appointing Grand Committees, and in ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pelling a Member for betraying the Prote<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtant and Engliſh Intereſt, which took up ſome time and debate in the Houſe.</p>
            <p>On <hi>Wedneſday 12th.</hi> beſides the Houſe receiving Petitions about undue Returns, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> the Act of Recognition, being ſent down from the Lords, was thrice read, and paſs'd, with a Vote, that no other Bill afterward ſhou'd be read more than once in a day.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Thurſday</hi> the <hi>13th.</hi> was taken up partly in receiving the Submiſſion of the foremen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned expelled Member, and diſcharging him out of Cuſtody; and partly in debating the Priviledge of the Houſe about Poſt Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters: It had been firſt moved on the <hi>10th.</hi> but one of the Secretaries then acquainting the Houſe, that his Excellency wou'd take care to Iſſue an Order to the Poſtmaſter for franking them; the Debate was let fall. And on the next day after, the Houſe re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:49925:6"/>their Letters free, having paid for them till then; but this day one of the Members informed the Houſe, that the Order for it took place only from <hi>Tueſday</hi> the <hi>11th.</hi> which was looked upon to make the Priviledge precarious, and wholly at the Lord Lieute<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants diſcretion; after ſome debate there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon, and urging Preſidents of the King's Meſſengers carrying the Members Letters free before the erection of the Poſt Office; It was voted for this and other Reaſons, in or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der to aſſert the Priviledge of the Houſe, that it was their Right to have their Letters free; which Vote at the Requeſt of ſome of the Members, was afterwards ordered not to be printed.</p>
            <p>On <hi>Friday</hi> and <hi>Saturday</hi> the <hi>14th.</hi> &amp; <hi>15th.</hi> the Houſe proceeded to take into Conſide<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration that part of his Excellency's Speech, relating to a Supply for their Majeſties; the firſt motion for it having been made, and ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>conded on <hi>Friday</hi> by ſome of them, who have ſince born the marks of the Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments Diſpleaſure.</p>
            <p>One of the Secretaries laid before the Houſe an imperfect State of the Revenue for the enſuing Year, and Copies affirmed of the
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:49925:6"/>Eſtabliſhments Civil and Military; and in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formed them, that his Majeſty (by reaſon of the waſted condition of this Kingdom) in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tending to remit a conſiderable part of the Quit and Crown Rents, a Sum of 64500 <abbr>
                  <hi>l.</hi>
               </abbr> was neceſſary to ſupply the Deficiencies of the Revenue for a year, beginning the <hi>25th. March,</hi> 1693.</p>
            <p>The granting of a Supply hereupon came to be fully debated; the great Poverty of the Kingdom in almoſt all the parts thereof, and the vaſt quantities of Land untenanted, and abſolutely waſte, and the inability of moſt perſons to pay even the ſtanding Revenue of the Quit Rent was repreſented; as like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe the great Obligations both of Duty and Gratitude which this Kingdom lay un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der to their Majeſties, and the grateful ſenſe which they ought to have of the vaſt expence of Blood and Treaſure <hi>England</hi> has already been at, were recognized and urged with their due Weight. And it was Reſolved, That nothing leſs than abſolute neceſſity ſhou'd make this Kingdom a Charge to <hi>England:</hi> Upon the whole matter, the Houſe came to this unanimous Vote, That a Sum not ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeding 70000 <abbr>
                  <hi>l.</hi>
               </abbr> ſhould be given as a Supply to their Majeſties.</p>
            <pb n="10" facs="tcp:49925:7"/>
            <p>On <hi>Monday</hi> the <hi>17th.</hi> the Houſe received ſome Reports from the Committee of Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viledges, concerning Burroughs newly erect<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed by King <hi>Charles</hi> II. which never ſent Members to Parliament before this Seſſion.</p>
            <p>But this being recommitted, the Houſe fell upon debate about another Member ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuſed for Crimes of like nature with the former; who on <hi>Saturday</hi> following being fully heard with his Witneſſes at the Bar, was alſo expelled.</p>
            <p>On <hi>Tueſday</hi> the <hi>18th.</hi> part of the Eſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bliſhment was read in the Committee of the whole Houſe, for conſidering of the Supply, as alſo the remaining part thereof on the <hi>Monday</hi> following; the Exceptions made a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt both, were waved.</p>
            <p>At this time ſeveral Committees did with great Application enquire into the Embezel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments of the forfeited Lands and Goods, which as yet had yielded nothing in pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portion to what it was ſuppoſed they might. The Members very well knew, that both real and perſonal Eſtates, to a conſiderable value, had been ſeized in their Reſpective Counties, and were witneſſes of the foul Practices that had been uſed in the managing
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:49925:7"/>and diſpoſal of them: They knew alſo, that their Majeſties Revenue wou'd be made more conſiderable for the future, by detect<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing and puniſhing the paſt Miſmanagements and Frauds. And accordingly the Houſe came to a Vote on <hi>Thurſday</hi> the <hi>20th.</hi> (<hi>Wed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſday</hi> being the Monthly Faſt) that it was a great breach of Truſt, and a Grievance, for any intruſted with the management of their Majeſties Revenue, to take to Farm a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny of the forfeited Intereſts.</p>
            <p>Several things of this kind being proved to be done by <hi>William C—d,</hi> 
               <abbr>Eſq</abbr> (one of the late Commiſſioners of the Revenue) be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the Committee of Grievances (as alſo great Quantities of Goods, and Stock, by him ſeized and unaccounted for;) he inſiſted on Priviledge as a Member of the Houſe of Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons of <hi>England;</hi> whereof the Houſe being informed, thought fit to proceed only in tak<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Examinations touching matter of Fail; but wou'd not oblige him to any defence after his inſiſting on his Priviledge.</p>
            <p>The Houſe alſo agreed to another Report from the ſaid Committee, that the continu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Papiſts in the Army, or ſuffering them to have ſerviceable Horſes or Arms, was at this
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:49925:8"/>juncture of dangerous Conſequence to this Kingdom; and Voted an Addreſs hereupon for Remedy thereof: And being inform<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed that his Excellency had cauſed divers ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpected Perſons to be apprehended, and ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral Troops to be ſent down to ſuppreſs ſome <hi>Iriſh</hi> who were out in Arms, voted their humble Thanks to be preſented to him.</p>
            <p>On <hi>Friday</hi> the <hi>21ſt.</hi> a Bill for confirming the Acts of Settlement and Explanation, which had been brought in on the <hi>12th.</hi> and had been twice read, was, according to the Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der of the day, debated in a Committee of the whole Houſe; it is certain, there could hardly have come a Bill to the Commons of this Kingdom with a more welcome Title than this; four parts in five of them having Eſtates dependant on the Acts of Settlement, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and therefore it will be much wondred that it ſhould occaſion any matter of Debate to them; but upon conſidering thereof, they cou'd not find one line in the whole Bill, which they could allow of, neither was there one word offer'd in defence thereof; but they declared it to be a Bill of ſuch pernici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous Contexture as inſtead of confirming, it wou'd have unſettled the greateſt part of the
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:49925:8"/>Eſtates of this Kingdom; and ſeveral of the Members cou'd not avoid being poſſeſſed with Jealouſies, that ſuch a Bill ſhou'd be tender'd them.</p>
            <p>On <hi>Saturday</hi> the <hi>22d.</hi> the Lord Lieu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tenant ſignify'd in a Meſſage to the Houſe, that this Seſſion wou'd not continue above a fortnight longer, and therefore re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>commended the ſpeedy Proceeding on ſuch Bills as were, or ſhou'd be brought before them; upon which they voted, that no more private Petitions ſhou'd be received.</p>
            <p>On <hi>Monday</hi> the <hi>24th.</hi> a Bill (which had been brought in on the <hi>18th.</hi>) for declaring all Attainders, and other Acts made in the late pretended Parliament void, was read the firſt time; the Title of this was no leſs ſpecious, than that for confirming the Act of Settle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> but the Houſe found it for their Majeſties Service, and the Honour of the Proteſtants of <hi>Ireland,</hi> to preſerve the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cords of the <hi>Iriſh</hi> Barbarity; which they cou'd not do without rejecting this Bill, becauſe it requir'd the ſaid Records to be taken off the File.</p>
            <p>Then they proceeded in a Committee of
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:49925:9"/>the whole Houſe, to conſider of ways to raiſe the Sum voted for a Supply.</p>
            <p>Two Mony Bills had been ſent to the Houſe on <hi>Saturday</hi> the <hi>22d.</hi> which were tranſmit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted from <hi>England</hi> under the Great Seal there; the Conſtitution of this Kingdom (ſince <hi>Poyning's</hi> Act, <hi>10th.</hi> H. 7.) requiring, that all Bills ſhou'd be ſo tranſmitted before they are paſſed into Laws here. One of thoſe Bills was for an Additional Exciſe; and the other for a Tax upon Corn: Theſe were ordered by the Houſe to be laid on the Table, and not to be read till ſome Expedient might be found, for a Difficulty that aroſe upon the bringing in theſe Bills.</p>
            <p>It has always been conceived the Origi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nal Right of the Commons, that Mony Bills ſhould take their Riſe in their Houſe, &amp; that as well the <hi>Quantum,</hi> as the method of raiſing it, ſhould be determined by them; the Houſe lookt upon this to be their inherent Funda<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mental Right, and that the ſame was not tak<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>en away by any Act of Parliament in this Kingdom; as in reaſon they thought none cou'd be ſo good Judges of the propereſt and eaſieſt way of taxing the Subject, as they, and even ſince <hi>Poyning</hi>'s Act, thoſe Rights of
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:49925:9"/>the Houſe are found Aſſerted in the Journals, on the bringing in of Mony Bills, whereof they did not prepare the Heads, and it is found to be a ſtanding Order in the ſaid Journals, That no Bill to Tax the Subject be brought into the Houſe without leave of the Houſe firſt obtained.</p>
            <p>But the Houſe conſidering, that their Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſties Occaſions required an immediate Sup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ply, and that probably, there might not be time allowed during this Seſſion, for Bills of their own preparing to be returned from <hi>England,</hi> according to Form, they were ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſitated to conſider how to reconcile theſe points.</p>
            <p>The firſt Expedient thought on was this, The Additional Exciſe Bill, of the two, ſeem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed moſt conſiſtent with the State of this Kingdom to be paſſed into an Act; tho the Houſe obſerved ſeveral Matters of juſt Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ception in it, as the inequality of Taxing dif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferent Liquors, the Taxing of ſome Liquors under the notion of an Additional Duty, which had not been Taxed before, and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinuing the former Incertainty of Meaſures; to be relieved againſt which laſt, a Petition of the Brewers had been preferred, and lay up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:49925:10"/>the Table, ſetting forth, that the Kings Du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty had been of late (by the means of Sir <hi>James Shaen,</hi> and others, the then Farmers of the Revenue, who were likewiſe Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners of the Exciſe, and conſequently Judges for their own Advantages) levyed by them of a Gallon of 217 Cubical Inches, tho for ſeveral years after the firſt paſſing the Act of Exciſe in this Kingdom, the meaſures by which the King's Officers then levyed that Duty (and by which the Brewers always have, and are now by Law obliged to ſell is a Gallon of 282 Inches, propoſing withal ſuch an encreaſe of Duty to be made, as ſhou'd anſwer the loſs the Revenue might ſuſtain by Regulation of the Meaſure. This Petition and Complaint, how reaſonable ſoever it might be in it ſelf, was not thought fit to be taken into conſideration, leſt it might retard the reading and paſſing the ſaid Bill.</p>
            <p>So that Poſtponing this and the other Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceptions, the Houſe thought an Expedient might be found for paſſing this Bill as it was, by voting firſt an Additional Duty exactly correſponding with the ſaid Bill in all the parts of it: And theſe Heads ſo prepared, being tender'd to the Lord Lieutenant and
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:49925:10"/>Council, to be drawn into a Bill and tranſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted, the Houſe might receive the Bill al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ready ſent as tranſmitted from <hi>England,</hi> and framed on their heads: And accordingly they paſſed the ſaid Vote for ſuch Additional Exciſe.</p>
            <p>On <hi>Tueſday</hi> the <hi>25th.</hi> the Houſe received Reports from Committees, particularly con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning CivilBills, as of late practiced at Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſizes, without any Foundation in Law, upon pretence of being a more expeditious and cheap way of recovering Debts and Dama<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges; Which the Houſe voted to be Arbitrary, Illegal, and a Burthen to the Subject, and that an Addreſs ſhou'd be preſented to the Lord Lieutenant in Council, to prepare a Bill, which might anſwer what was of advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tage in this practice, without oppreſſing the Subject, by giving an unlimited Power to the Judges.</p>
            <p>Then by order of the day, the Houſe re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolved into a Committee to conſider the State of the Nation; and it being propoſed, that the beſt means to ſettle this Kingdom in a laſting Happineſs, wou'd be to find out the cauſes of its Miſery. The Committee reſol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved on, and voted, (among other Reaſons) theſe two following to be aſſigned for it;
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:49925:11"/>Firſt, the great countenance given to the <hi>Iriſh</hi> Papiſts in the Reign of K. <hi>C. 2d.</hi> and their be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing employ'd by the late King <hi>James.</hi> Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>condly, the obſtruction of the courſe of Juſtice by Illegal Protections, granted ſince the defeat at the <hi>Boyne.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>A motion was made in debate of this lat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, that particulars might be inſtanced, and the perſons who granted them named, to the end their Majeſties might know who they were that had ſo much abuſed their Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity committed to them; but ſome ſcrup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led it, becauſe of the great Characters they bore; and the Committee ſoon breaking up, this was deferred till its next Sitting, which was on the <hi>27th.</hi> and then it was only con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cluded (the Members being willing the Speaker ſhou'd reſume the Chair, in order to proceed on the Exciſe Bill) to name per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons at the next Sitting thereof, which was appointed on the <hi>29th.</hi> and ſo from day to day; but this Committee ſtill gave place to that for conſidering the Supply, &amp; no Report was ever made to the Houſe from the ſaid Committee; but on <hi>November</hi> the <hi>1ſt.</hi> it was ordered to ſit on the <hi>4th.</hi> and nothing to intervene.</p>
            <pb n="19" facs="tcp:49925:11"/>
            <p>
               <hi>Wedneſday</hi> and <hi>Thurſday</hi> the <hi>26th.</hi> &amp; <hi>27th.</hi> were taken up in debating other Expedients, for the difficulty mention'd on <hi>Monday,</hi> that then offer'd, not being found to anſwer the Ends; after ſeveral propoſed, ſome that were moved by Members, who had preſſed the Reading of the Bill, and were ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>po<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ed to ſpeak what was Agreeable to the Government, took place, which were to aſſert the Priviledges of the Houſe by a Vote, to read the Exciſe Bill in order to paſs it, and reject the Corn Bill: Accordingly this Exciſe Bill was thus read, and ſo ſucceſſively every day till it was paſſed.</p>
            <p>On <hi>Friday</hi> the <hi>28th.</hi> the Corn Bill, accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the former Expedient, was rejected, and the reaſon given, becauſe it had not its Riſe in the Houſe of Commons.</p>
            <p>The Houſe then Reſolved it ſelf into a Committee, and proceeded to conſider fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther of Method to anſwer the Contents of the Corn Bill by ſome other Tax, that their Majeſties might receive the full Supply de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded.</p>
            <p>It was conſidered, that the Corn Bill wou'd have yielded no Mony until <hi>Summer,</hi> 1693. and part thereof not until <hi>Michaelmas</hi> fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowing;
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:49925:12"/>and they thought they might by other means raiſe the Sum much ſooner, and more equally.</p>
            <p>The ſeveral ways of raiſing Mony, was throughly debated; and at length the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mittee unanimouſly agreed on a Poll Bill for ſeveral Reaſons, of which the following was not the leaſt: They were in hopes to have paſſed this Bill before the end of the Seſſion by Adjournment, till a Bill prepared accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to Heads agreed on by them, might have been tranſmitted into <hi>England,</hi> and returned hither to be paſſed; this wou'd have been an immediate Fund, which with the Exciſe Bill wou'd have amounted to much more than the Sum required.</p>
            <p>They who were for this in the Houſe, cou'd not ſuppoſe that theſe Proceedings wou'd have been any ways diſpleaſing to the Government.</p>
            <p>The ſame day three ingroſſed Bills were ſent down from the Lords, <hi>viz.</hi> an Act for puniſhing Mutineers and Deſerters; an Act for Encouragement of Proteſtant Strangers; and An Act for preventing Vexatious Suits. Of theſe the Bill for encouraging Proteſtant Strangers, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> was read, &amp; in three days paſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed: And the Bill for preventing Vexatious
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:49925:12"/>Suits was twice read, and committed to a ſelect Committee; but it was not Reported to the Houſe at the time of the Prorogation.</p>
            <p>On <hi>Monday</hi> the <hi>31ſt.</hi> (<hi>Saturday</hi> having been ſpent in the laſt reading and paſſing the Bill for an Additional Exciſe, and in debates a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout a controverted Election) a Bill for ſet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tling a <hi>Militia</hi> in this Kingdom (which had been brought into the Houſe on the <hi>24th.</hi>) was read the firſt time; but it propoſing a much greater Number to be raiſed upon ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral Counties, than there were Proteſtant Inhabitants in the ſaid Countys, and lodging too great a Power in Commiſſioners of Array, for theſe and other Reaſons was rejected; however, the Houſe being ſenſible, that a Bill for ſettling a <hi>Militia,</hi> wou'd be very re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quiſite for this Kingdom, reſolved to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſider of it on <hi>Tueſday</hi> the firſt of <hi>November,</hi> in a Committee of the whole Houſe; and then came to a Vote, that a <hi>Militia</hi> by Law eſtabliſhed, was abſolutely neceſſary for pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerving the Peace of this Kingdom; and made a conſiderable Progreſs in forming of it, and appointed to proceed on it again on the <hi>3d.</hi> of <hi>November.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>A Committee having formerly been ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:49925:13"/>amongſt other things, to inſpect what Laws had been made in <hi>England</hi> ſince the 10. <hi>H.</hi> 7. and were fit to be enacted in this Kingdom; and the Houſe purſuant to their Report, having voted ſeveral of them in par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticular to be neceſſary; ordered the ſaid Committee to attend the Lord Lieutenant in Council with the ſaid Votes, and humbly to deſire that Bills might be prepared accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dingly; but his Excellency not coming to Council on the day the Houſe was informed his Excellency wou'd be for this purpoſe at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended there: The Houſe on <hi>Wedneſday</hi> the <hi>2d.</hi> ordered an Addreſs to be made to his Excellency, to know his pleaſure therein; and his Excellency thereupon was pleaſed to appoint <hi>Friday</hi> the <hi>4th.</hi> in the Afternoon, to be attended with the ſaid Votes.</p>
            <p>At the ſame time his Excellency was alſo pleaſed to accept of the Commons Addreſs in behalf of their Chaplain, and in a moſt ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liging manner, to declare, that their Addreſs ſhou'd be always acceptable to him.</p>
            <p>This day alſo the Houſe received a Meſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſage from his Excellency recommending to them, the taking the Bill for puniſhing Mu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tineers and Deſerters by Martial Law into
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:49925:13"/>ſpeedy Conſideration. This Bill was brought into the Houſe the <hi>28th.</hi> of <hi>October,</hi> and had been twice Read and Committed; one of the Secretaries preſſed, that it might be taken from the Committee, and immediately read a third time; but the Houſe conceiving it more proper to be debated in a Committee, Reſolved accordingly, and thinking the former Number thereof too few to debate a matter of ſo great moment, ordered, that all that came, ſhou'd have Votes, and to be Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ported next Morning.</p>
            <p>On <hi>Thurſday</hi> the <hi>3d.</hi> the ſaid Bill being Reported with the Amendments, was reject<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed by the Houſe, it containing not one fifth part of the Act made in <hi>England</hi> to that pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe; and the part in that <hi>Engliſh</hi> Act re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lating to the good of the Subject, and the Kingdom in general (by obliging the Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers to orderly Quarters, faithful Payment of the Souldiers, and to juſt and true Mu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters, being quite left out: And whereas the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Act is to continue only for one Year, this was to continue for three years, and from thence to the end of the next Seſſion of Parliament. But a Committee was then appointed to meet that Afternoon,
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:49925:14"/>and prepare Heads of a Bill, agreeable to the ſaid <hi>Engliſh</hi> Act.</p>
            <p>Soon after the rejecting this Bill, ſeveral of the Members were informed that the Parliament wou'd be immediately Prorogued or D<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ſſolved.</p>
            <p>A large Report was then made to the Houſe, from a ſelect Committee, repreſenting Diſcoveries of ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry great Conſequence, drawn from the Accounts relating to the forſeited <hi>Iriſh</hi> Eſtates both Real and Perſonal; but the Houſe receiving information, That his Excellency was come to the Houſe of Lords. This Report was ordered to lye on the Table.</p>
            <p>A Meſſage was brought by the Uſher of the Black Rod, requiring the Houſe of Commons im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mediately to attend his Excellency in the Lord's Houſe.</p>
            <p>The Houſe accordingly went up to the Houſe of Lords, his Excellency being ſeated in his Robes, gave the Royal Aſſent to four Bills, <hi>viz.</hi> The Act of Recognition, The Act of Exciſe, The Act for Encouragement of Proteſtant Strangers, and the Act for taking Affidavits in the Country; the Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny Bill was paſſed, with the uſual Form, <hi>viz.</hi> that their Majeſties thank their Loyal Subjects, and ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cepted their Benevolence.</p>
            <p>The Houſe were ſomewhat ſurprized at this unexpected Reſolution, having expected to ſit at leaſt the next day, and did not apprehend what occaſion they had given of Diſpleaſure to his Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cellency to put ſo ſudden an end to the Seſſion<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> when the day before he expreſſed himſelf ſo favou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rably to them, in anſwer to their Addreſſes, and aſſigned them the day after this for the Committee
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:49925:14"/>to attend him in Council; but they were more ſurprized to hear his Excellency charge them in his Speech, <hi>That they had not anſwered the Ends for which they were called together, but had behaved them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves undutifully and ungratefully, in invading their Majeſties Perogative;</hi> a Charge of ſuch a nature as ſounded very harſh in the Ears of Gentlemen, who looked upon themſelves, and the reſt of the Proteſtants in this Kingdom, to be as obſequiouſly devoted to their Majeſties Intereſt, as any of their Majeſties Subject; a Qualification and Temper, which they knew was not likely to recommend them to thoſe amongſt whom they lived, and therefore could not, but with the higheſt regret and trouble, hear his Excellency caſt them off from their juſt Claim to the moſt unfeigned Dutifulneſs and Affection to their Majeſties (which they held as dear to them as their Lives,) and at the ſame time expoſe them to the Inſultings of their moſt implacable and malitious Adverſaries, who they knew were ever warchful and ready to improve all Advantages againſt them; who cou'd not but look upon a Proteſtant Parliament with trouble, and therefore rejoyced to ſee it meet with ſuch Treatment.</p>
            <p>They reflected on what they had done, that cou'd poſſibly occaſion ſo ſevere a Cenſure; but his Excellency in his next Sentence, was pleaſed to clear this point to them, by referring to their print<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Votes of the <hi>27th.</hi> of <hi>October,</hi> That it is the ſole and undoubted Right of the Houſe of Commons, to prepare Heads of Mony Bills, and to their reject<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing a Mony Bill the next day, becauſe it had not it's Riſe in their Houſe.</p>
            <pb n="26" facs="tcp:49925:15"/>
            <p>This the Gentlemen of the Houſe of Commons, cou'd not but very much admire of, conſidering how maturely (and with what deference to their Majeſties Prerogative) thoſe things had been de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bated in the Houſe; and not only conſented to, but firſt propoſed as an Expedient, by ſome who have always both before and ſince, comply'd with the Directions of the Government without Reſerve; all the Votes relating to the Expedient, being like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe Reſolved without one Negative Voice.</p>
            <p>But for theſe Reaſons, his Excellency declared, <hi>That he thought himſelf obliged to proteſt againſt thoſe Votes and the Entries of them in the Commons Jour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nals; and accordingly he did in full Parliament Proteſt againſt them, and ordered the Clerk of the Houſe of Lords, to Read the ſaid Proteſt, and enter it in the Jour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nals of the ſaid Houſe,</hi> without its being put to the Queſtion, or Voted there: And then the Lord Chan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cellor (by his Excellencies Command) Prorogued the Parliament to the <hi>6th.</hi> of <hi>April</hi> next.</p>
            <p>It muſt be owned, That in this Speech of his Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cellency, as it was after printed; his Charge a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt the Houſe of Commons is not in ſo ſevere Terms, as thoſe before ſet down, which yet were the preciſe Expreſſions as they were ſpoken, they making too deep an Impreſſion in the Minds of thoſe who heard them, to be eaſily forgotten.</p>
            <p>It may alſo be obſerved, that his Excellency re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferred to their printed Votes of the <hi>27th.</hi> of <hi>Octob.</hi> Tho no printed Votes have been publickly ſeen, ſince thoſe of the <hi>25th.</hi> But in his Excellencies printed Speech, the word <hi>Printed</hi> is left out.</p>
            <p>It cannot be avoided to mention here as an effect of this unparalell'd Diſpleaſure of his Excellency,
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:49925:15"/>againſt the Houſe of Commons, that within few days after the Prorogation, one of the Members was affronted in the Caſtle, by Brigadeer <hi>Stewart,</hi> and Mr. <hi>Watſon,</hi> Steward to his Excellency, with his <hi>White Rod</hi> in his hand, and others his Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cellency's Servants, without the leaſt Provo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cation. This was complained of by the Speaker to his Excellency, but no ſatisfaction given.</p>
            <p>Several of the Members were hereupon con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vinced, That thoſe Perſons who dreaded the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceedings of the Houſe, were to the misfortune of this Nation, in ſo great Credit with his Excellen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cy, as to occaſion the harſh Expreſſions uſed upon the Prorogation, and had from thence juſt reaſon to ſuſpect that thoſe very Perſons wou'd prevail on him to repreſent the Commons to their Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſties, under the ſame unhappy Characters, which had in open Parliament been fixed upon them; to avoid which, and likewiſe to prevent the Miſeries threatning this Kingdom, in caſe their Majeſties are not informed of the true State of this Nation: They Reſolved on the like methods, which on ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral occaſions had been practic'd by the People of this Kingdom in former Reigns; and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore deſired Sir <hi>Arthur Rawdon,</hi> Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> Sir <hi>Arthur Langford,</hi> and Mr. <hi>Anneſley</hi> (four of the Members) to deliver a Petition to his Excellency, for leave to ſend Agents to attend their Majeſties in <hi>England.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>This they did on the <hi>7th.</hi> of <hi>November,</hi> and his Excellency was pleaſed to ſay, <hi>That his Majeſty was the Proteſtans Agent, and they ſhou'd have leave to go for</hi> England, <hi>to beg their Majeſties Pardon for their Seditious and Riotous Aſſemblies.</hi> Not admitting
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:49925:16" rendition="simple:additions"/>of a Reply, but concluding, <hi>He had no other Anſwer to give them.</hi> The Lord Chancellor afterwards told one of them, who preſented this Petition; <hi>that they had done illegally, and that it was Reſolved in Council that they ſhou'd be Proſecuted.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>In concluſion, it muſt be obſerved, That as here never was any Parliament more intirely devoted to their Princes Service, nor more ready to the ut<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moſt to expreſs their Duty and Gratitude on all occaſions, ſo few Aſſemblies cou'd have employ'd themſelves more induſtriouſly and diligently for the Publick Service than they did. It might not indeed have been wondered, if (after ſo long a diſcontinuance of Parliaments in this Kingdom) the Members of this Houſe had not at firſt fallen readily into the Methods of Buſineſs, but by what they diſpatched in the ſhort time of their Sitting (if the buſineſs of the ſeveral Committees be conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dered, as well as what is recited in the foregoing Account) it muſt be allowed, That they want<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed neither Diligence nor Publick Spirits in laying themſelves out for their Majeſties Intereſt; their Committees ſitting frequently till eleven a Clock at Night, and the Houſe never riſing before two; ſo that if their Services, have not met with ſuch acceptance, as perſons ſo diſpoſed chiefly deſired and aimed at; it is their Unhappineſs and the Nations, but cannot be accounted their Fault.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
